ed3000 出品
他们派我来谈服务租赁合同
They sent me to negotiate a service lease.
达成协议了吗  达成了
- We got a deal? - We got a deal.
情况不太妙  给我点时间
This ain't gonna be good. Give me a second.
有多糟
How bad?
这个问题不好回答
That's a tricky one to answer.
你和内特能处理吗
Is it something you and Nate can handle?
他们会从三个方向来攻击你们
They're gonna hit you from three directions.
保险公司  受害者家属和TTP
Insurance company, victims' families and TTP.
这里没看到死掉的毒贩
I don't see any dead drug dealers over here.
操
Fuck.
爸爸
Daddy!
宝贝  你好
-  Baby. -  Hi.
我的小天使越来越漂亮了
You get prettier every day, little angel.
你是诺里斯家的宝贝吗
You baby Norris?
库珀
Cooper.
我觉得叫宝贝更好
I think baby's better.
咱们的宝贝怎么样
How's our baby?
这是他第一天上班
It's his first day.
第一天都不容易
First days ain't easy.
再高点
Higher!
你们全家都在油田工作吗
Your whole family works the patch?
这里谁家不是全家都在油田
Everybody's whole family works the patch.
努力工作是值得的
It's better you work for it real hard.
这样就没人能夺走你的成果
You know, that way nobody can take it away.
去拿24英吋的管钳来
Go get the 24-inch pipe wrench.
早安  米德兰-敖德萨
Good morning, Midland-Odessa.
现在是周六早上7点53分
It's 7:53 a.m. on a Saturday.
对其他地方来说是周末
That's a weekend in the rest of the world,
但现在原油每桶87美元
but with just over 87 a barrel,
油田地区暂时没有周末可言
there's no more weekends in the basin for a while.
钱钱钱钱钱
Money, money, money, money, money.
今天最高气温94度
Looking at a high of 94 degrees today.
别忘了今晚凌晨2点
And don't forget, tonight at 2 a.m.
要调快时钟
those clocks spring forward.
哪有今晚凌晨2点这种说法
There's no such thing as tonight at 2 a.m.
应该说明天凌晨2点
There's tomorrow at 2 a.m.
如果凌晨2点还没睡就是今晚
If you're still awake at 2 a.m., it's tonight.
听起来像乡村歌曲
That sounds like a country song.
确实像乡村歌曲
It does sound like a country song.
该放首乡村歌曲了
I think it's time to play a country song.
你觉得呢  我赞成
- What do you think? -  I think it is.
来听听威士忌迈尔斯乐队
How about a little Whiskey Myers
这首歌能助你度过94度的下午
and what it takes to make it through a 94-degree afternoon?
就放坏药物这首歌
That'd be a little "Bad Medicine."
别吃那垃圾了  会要你命的
You got to quit eating that shit. It's gonna kill you.
说这话的人每天抽两包烟
Says the two-pack-a-day smoker?
你去过日本吗
You ever been to Japan?
那个国家人人都抽烟
The whole country smokes.
90岁老头抽着无过滤嘉宝烟
Ninety-year-old men sucking on filterless Pall Malls,
还能在公园里打一小时太极
then doing an hour of tai chi in the park.
中国也这样  意大利也一样
Same thing in China, same thing in Italy,
他们甚至都不运动
and they don't even exercise.
就喝酒  吃意面  做爱
All they do is drink wine, eat pasta and fuck.
你知道这三个国家有什么共同点吗
You know what those three countries have in common?
肺癌甚至都不在
Lung cancer ain't even
十大死因之列
in the top ten leading causes of death.
所以不是香烟的问题
So it ain't cigarettes.
糖和那些垃圾才会要命
It's sugar and shit like that that kills you.
我跟你说
I'm telling you.
早安  爸爸  早安  宝贝
- Morning, Daddy. - Oh, morning, baby.
嗨  嗯
- Hi. - Mm.
她是在比喻意义上叫你爸爸吗
Is she using Daddy as a metaphor?
那是我女儿
That's my daughter.
难怪你抽这么多烟
Now I know why you smoke so much.
是啊
Yeah.
他走了
He left.
亲爱的  是你让他走的
Well, honey, you told him to.
但他不该真走啊
But he's not supposed to do it.
他应该改变想法
He's supposed to change the way he feels
然后照我说的做
and then do what I want.
男人都他妈怎么了
What the fuck is wrong with men?!
我知道我们有规矩  但是
I know we got a rule, but, um...
我只是想  你知道  理清思路
I'm just, you know, kind of working it out.
完全理解
- Completely understood. -
以为你轮班结束了  有人报告说
- Thought your hitch was over. - Well, someone called in
闪电击中了储油罐
a lightning strike on a holding tank
就在我准备离开的时候
right as I was fucking leaving town.
烧掉了  对  烧掉了
- Burned it up? - Yeah, burned it up.
告诉你  如果想清除野生麻黄树
I'll tell you one thing, if you want to clear that mesquite out,
就用压裂水浸泡树根
you just soak those roots in frack water.
戴尔
Hey, Dale,
你考虑过要不要
you think you might want to try
喝杯咖啡什么的
having a coffee or something?
再喝咖啡我的心脏就要爆炸了
If I have another coffee, my heart's gonna explode.
这附近谁家的填土好
Who we using for fill dirt around here?
国家工地或顶级沙土和砾石公司
National Site or TopSoil Sand and Gravel.
对  对
Yeah, yeah.
戴尔  别穿着靴子
Hey, Dale, don't walk on the...
踩在该死的地毯上
fucking carpet in those boots.
这个邋遢的混蛋
That sloppy son of a bitch.
确实
Right?
我的天
Oh, shit.
上帝啊
God!
那是什么鬼
The fuck is that?
可能是水槽里的蜘蛛
Spider in the sink maybe?
不  这不像看到蜘蛛时的叫声
No, that didn't sound like a spider scream.
浴室里有强奸犯
There's a rapist in the bathroom!
爸爸  浴室里有强奸犯
Dad, there's a rapist in the bathroom!
等等  等等  有什么
Wait, wait, hang on. There's a what?
浴室里有强奸犯
There's a rapist in the bathroom!
什么  浴室里有  对
- What? A rapist in the bath-- - Yes.
去  等我  去厨房等我
Well, ju... wait-wait for me in the kitchen.
为什么不告诉我有女人在
Why didn't you tell me you had a woman over?
不是别的女人  是我女儿
I don't have a woman over, I have my daughter over.
汤米  你女儿就是个女人
Tommy, your daughter is a woman.
你想再挨一下吗
You want to get hit again?
你能站起来吗
- Can you stand up? -
要心脏药吗
You want a heart pill or something?
阿司匹林  抽屉最上层
Aspirin. Top drawer.
这里有咀嚼片  如果你想要的话
There's chewables in here if you want some.
这个也能嚼
These chew fine.
她要住多久
How long is she staying?
几天而已
Couple of days.
请向她说明浴室门锁的事
Explain to her the locks on the bathroom doors, please.
我会说的  谢谢
- I'll do it. - Thank you.
那真是太好了  先生
That would be very nice of you, sir.
我说了我会说  该死的
Yeah, I said I'll do it. Goddamn it.
要我扶你起来吗  不用  不用  我没事
- You want me to help you up? - No, no, I'll be fine.
就想一个人静一会儿
Just want to sit here by myself for a minute.
亲爱的  这是内森
Honey, this is Nathan.
他是石油和天然气律师
He's an oil and gas attorney.
另一个室友是戴尔
My other roommate is Dale.
他是所谓的石油工程师
He's what they call a petroleum engineer.
现在正在楼上  角膜破裂
He's the one upstairs right now with a ruptured cornea
还有医生说的心肌梗塞
and what doctors call a myocardial infarction.
普通人管这叫心脏病发作
Regular folks call that a heart attack,
就是你戳瞎他眼睛时给他造成的
which is what you gave him when you poked his fucking eye out.
所以为了避免再次发生混乱
So I tell you what, just to prevent further confusion,
咱们都同意进浴室时
what do you say we all lock the bathroom door
锁上门如何
when we're in it?
不用说第二遍
Don't got to tell me twice.
我的浴室在楼下
My bathroom's downstairs.
我想不出任何理由  内特
- I can't come up with a reason-- -  Nate,
把该死的门锁上行吗
just lock the fucking door, will you?
这样就不用想理由了
Then we don't have to worry about reasons.
不会再有这种事了
There won't be one.
太好了  我的一天开始了
Oh, goodie. My day begins.
是
Yeah.
你在路上了吗
You on your way?
在路上去哪儿
On my way where?
你不知道
You don't know?
我当然不知道  沃尔特  到底是什么事
Well, clearly not, Walt. What do I not fucking know?
伙计  你们那边出井喷了
Buddy, y'all had a blowout.
天呐  迈克
Jesus, Mike,
我是在给你
you're acting like I'm not trying to give you
价值两千二百万的生意
$22 million dollars' worth of business.
看在老天的份上  能不能在价格上商量一下
For fuck's sake, can you work with me on the price?
该死  我买一打甜甜圈
Goddamn it, I buy a dozen doughnuts,
都能多送一个
someone throws one in for free.
我提醒你  你又不是这个州
Need I remind you, you are not the only person
唯一一个卖中空钢管的人
selling hollowed-out steel in this fucking state?
谢谢
Thank you.
天呐  喂
Christ. Hey.
谢泼德-黑斯廷斯派律师来了
Shepherd-Hastings is sending an attorney out.
他们的飞机中午到  你能去接一下吗
Their plane lands at noon. Can you pick him up?
长官  我们这边出井喷了
Sir, we've had a blowout.
天...
Oh, f...
见鬼
God dang it.
我们的人在现场吗
Was our crew on location?
不知道  我正在赶过去
I don't know, I'm en route.
让律师自己租车吧
Just tell the attorney to get a rental car.
房子里还有空房间吗
All right, is-is there room at the house,
还是要帮他们订酒店
or are they gonna need a hotel?
房子里有空房间
There's room in the house.
有什么消息
Well, you find anything out,
跟我说一声
you let me know.
你一定是第一个知道的  放心
You'll be the first one, trust me.
操
Fuck.
哦
Ooh.
今天天气真好
Beautiful out today.
是啊
Sure is.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
沃尔特  嘿
- Walt! -  Yo!
有抽油工吗
Is there a pumper here?
抽油工  有
- Pumper? - Yes,
该死  我是说油井工人
a goddamn oilman, Walt.
对  有个人正跟急救人员在一起
Yeah, there's a guy down here with EMS right now.
你看见有人关阀门吗
Did you see anybody shutting any valves off?
没看见
I did not.
我告诉你  这算什么
Tell you what, you think this is bad?
要是储油罐爆了
Those holding tanks go up,
能把你炸到阿比林去
they'll blow your ass to Abilene.
哪辆救护车
Which ambulance?
就在那边
Right down there.
让他们撤回去
Get 'em back!
他还好吗
Is he all right?
库珀  你还好吗
Cooper, are you all right?
他鼓膜震破了
He blew his eardrum.
你其他同事呢
Where's the rest of your crew?
你其他同事在哪儿
Where's the rest of your crew?!
听着  你知道井口底部
Listen, you know the Christmas tree
那个圣诞树形阀吗
at the bottom of the wellhead?
知道
I know it.
你把阀门关了吗
Did you shut the valve off?
我不知道  不知道
- I don't know. - You don't know?
沃尔特
Walt!
让所有人都撤回去
Get everybody back!
你要干什么
What are you doing?
你觉得呢
What do you think I'm doing?
让所有人都撤回去就行
Just keep everybody back.
该死
Ow, goddamn it.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
疼
Ow.
天呐
Oh, Jesus.
我去叫救护车
I'm gonna stop that ambulance.
别叫救护车
No, don't stop the ambulance.
你不去医院处理一下吗
You don't want to go to the hospital with that?
不  我想要根烟
No, I want a cigarette
还想喝点胡椒博士汽水
and a Dr Pepper.
冰柜在副驾驶那边
There's a cooler there, passenger side.
谢了
Appreciate you.
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
派消防队去M-TEX 1422号井
Get a fire crew out to M-TEX 1422.
井喷了  现在就喷了吗
- She's blowing. - She's blowing now?
对  就他妈现在  马上派人过来
Yes, right fucking now. Get 'em out here.
好的  我们马上来  好
- All right, we're on our way. - All right.
现在我想去医院了
Now I want to go to the hospital.
我的办公室应该安排了租车
I believe my office arranged a rental car for me.
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
停机坪上就有
It's on the tarmac.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗯
Hmm.
好像太显眼了
Seems a little excessive.
有低调一点的车吗
You have anything a little more unassuming?
您的办公室要求豪华轿车
Oh, your office asked for a luxury sedan.
能换辆低调点的吗
How about something a little more unassuming?
我不确定
I'm not sure...
就要辆不起眼的
Something that doesn't stand out.
这在米德兰一点都不起眼
Oh, that won't stand out in Midland.
但我不会开去敖德萨
I wouldn't drive it in Odessa.
知道了
Good to know.
我的宝贝乖不乖
Is my angel behaving?
你知道他们在上床吗
Did you know they've been having sex?
我猜到了  你看看他
I mean, I assumed. Look at this kid.
要是他们分手了  我可能会上他
If they ever break up, I might try to fuck him.
那你今天运气不错
Well, today's your lucky day, then.
天呐  他们分手了吗
Oh, no, they broke up?
为什么  因为他果然
- Why? - Well, because he turned out
就是我们想的那种人
to be exactly what we thought he was.
她怎么样
How's she taking it?
就像个17岁的小孩
Like a 17-year-old
从8岁起就没人管过她
who hasn't heard no since she was eight.
可怜的孩子
Poor thing.
听着  今天钻井平台出事了
So, listen, uh, there was an accident out today
库珀受伤了
on one of the rigs, and, uh,
伤得重吗
Cooper got hurt.
我们正在急诊室等检查结果
How hurt?
让我跟他说话
Well, we're at the ER now. They're checking him out.
亲爱的  不行  他在另一个房间
- Let me talk to him. - I can't, sweetie,
你怎么不跟他在一起
he's in another room.
你为什么不陪着他
Why aren't you with him?
你什么事都要扯到自己身上
Always got to make it about you.
对  我就是这样
Oh, yeah, that's what I'm doing.
什么事都扯到自己身上
Making it about me.
安斯利在哪儿  在家
- Where's Ainsley? - At the house.
跟一群吃了伟哥的石油工程师在一起
With a bunch of petroleum engineers
手机一震动就来劲那种
so hopped up on Cialis, they get a hard-on
都硬了
when their phone vibrates?
有库珀的消息我就给你打电话  行吗
Listen, as soon as I hear more about Cooper,
好吧
I'll call you back. Okay?
汤米  我话还没说完呢
Tommy, I am not done with you.
你知道离婚最大的好处就是
You know, one of the great joys of being divorced is,
不用听这些废话了
I don't have to listen to this shit.
好好享受沙滩吧  你胸挺不错
Enjoy the beach. Your tits look great.
别得梅毒就行
Don't get syphilis.
这建议真不错
That's always sound advice.
是啊  活着的真理
Yeah, words to live by.
我不用费力气解释了
Let me save you the trouble.
只是确保你脾脏没事
Just making sure the same thing didn't happen to your spleen.
还有其他地方疼吗
No other pain?
就我用锤子砸到的手疼
Just where I hit my hand with a fucking hammer.
让我看看
Let me see that.
我去叫个手外科医生来
I'm gonna call in a hand specialist.
接上这个是...
Reattaching this is--
就是小指一点点而已
It's just a tiny piece of a pinky.
我才不要做一年的手术
I ain't dicking around with 12 surgeries for a fucking year.
直接切了缝上就行
Just cut it off and sew up the fucking top.
我强烈建议你不要这样做
I would strongly advise you against that.
要么你来要么我自己来
Well, either you do it or I'll do it.
我不是外科医生
I'm not a surgeon.
让我叫外科医生来
Let me bring in the surgeon
我们可以商量...行吧  刚好这里
- and we can discuss... Okay. - Well, it just so happens
就有个外科医生  等等
- there's a surgeon right here. - Well, hold on.
这...
Oh, that...
好极了  就这样
- that's nice. - There she is.
注意你的腿
Hey, uh, watch your leg.
搞定了
There you go. Job done.
现在可以帮我缝合了吗
Now, you care to stitch it?
你刚毕业吧
Did you just get out of school?
你说有多大可能
Hey, what are the chances
它自己结痂
that, like, it just scabs over
过个月就好了
and in a month it's good as new?
你觉得呢  这种可能性
- What do you think? - The odds are
微乎其微
astronomically against that.
更可能的是你会感染葡萄球菌
What's more likely is, you get a staph infection
一个月后就得截肢了
and in a month we're amputating your arm.
我去叫护士准备缝合
I'll have a nurse prepare to suture.
谢谢
I appreciate that.
知道我儿子在哪个房间吗
- Mm-hmm. - You know what room
库珀·诺里斯
my son's in? Cooper Norris?
急诊室五号
Uh... ER Five.
我去看看他
I'm gonna go see him.
我觉得你最好先不要动...
I think it's best if you just sit tight--
准备好了就来找我
Just come get me when you're ready.
至少先包扎一下
At least cover it.
好吧
All right.
你真是一点也不着急啊
Boy, you sure ain't in no fucking hurry, are you?
找到他们了吗
Did you find 'em?
找到一个  是哪个
- One of them. - Which one?
现在无法确认
There ain't no way to know.
要和我一起去通知家属吗
You want to come with me? Notify next of kin?
不太想去
Not really.
你去吗
Will you?
去医院接我
Pick me up at the hospital.
该死
Shit.
你的手怎么了
What happened to your hand?
这是一个值得铭记的教训
Well, here's a life lesson worth filing away.
锤子和手打架  锤子必赢
When hammer hits hand, hammer wins.
该你说了
Your turn.
我也不知道
I don't know.
他们让我去卡车上拿管钳
They sent me to the truck to fetch a pipe wrench.
下一秒我就飞了出去
Next thing I know, I'm flying through the air.
就这样  三个寡妇六个孤儿
And just like that, three widows and six orphans.
八个孤儿
Eight orphans.
这就是三百个理由中的第一个
Here's reason number one of about 300
为什么你该找个更好的谋生方式
why you might want to find a better way of making a living.
我能干什么
What am I gonna do?
坐办公室卖芯片吗
Sit in an office and sell fucking computer chips?
对  也许可以
Yeah, maybe.
我知道该怎么做
I know what I'm gonna do.
等他们把我的手指缝好
When they sew up what's left of my fucking finger,
我就开车去路易斯家
I'm gonna drive over to Luis's house
告诉他妻子  她失去了丈夫和两个侄子
and tell his wife she's lost a husband and two nephews.
然后我要去阿曼多家
And then I'm going over to Armando's house
做同样的事
and do the same kind of thing.
再去埃尔维奥家
And then I'm going out to Elvio's house
告诉那个22岁的母亲
to tell a 22-year-old mother
赶紧去找份工作养家糊口
to break out the fucking want ads and get a job.
没时间悲伤  没时间哀悼
No time to grieve, no time to mourn.
因为银行不会等人
'Cause banks don't wait.
你也该看看求职广告了
You might want to look at the want ads yourself,
你这个自私的混蛋
you selfish little son of a bitch,
不然我就得和你妈
before I'm having the same conversation with your mother
说同样的话了
as I'm about to have with Elvio's wife.
我自私  那你算什么
If I'm so selfish, what does that make you?
一个负债50万的离婚酗酒鬼
A divorced alcoholic with $500,000 in debt...
而我还是幸运的那个
...and I'm one of the lucky ones.
加油  格蕾西
Come on, Gracie.
他们是独立承包商吗
Were they independent contractors?
不  是我们的人
No, they were ours.
知道到底发生什么事了吗
Any idea what the fuck happened?
抽油机很旧了
Well, it's a pretty old jack.
肯定是阀门的问题
It's gonna be one of the valves.
油罐阀门锈死了
Tank valve was rusted shut,
我估计其他阀门也一样
and I assume it's the same with the other ones.
有人用扳手敲击时产生火花
Somebody banged it with a wrench and created a spark
点燃了泄漏的天然气  我是这么猜的
and ignited that gas leak. That's my guess anyhow.
职业安全与健康署会得出同样结论吗
Is OSHA gonna come to the same conclusion?
他们也会这么假设
Well, they'll have the same assumption.
抽油机都融化了
That pumpjack melted like butter.
你看不出现场
You can't look at the site
能得出什么明确结论
and come to any kind of definite conclusion.
你打算怎么办
What do you want to do?
宝贝
Honey!
我想给这些家庭一笔钱
I want to make an offer to the families.
和解金吗
A settlement?
一笔帮他们渡过难关的礼物
A gift, just to get 'em through.
多少  25万每家
- How much? - 250 each.
宝贝  比赛要开始了  好  马上来
- Honey, they're about to start. - All right. I'll be right there.
能等一下吗  好
- Can you hold on one second? - Yeah.
加油  姑娘  冲啊
-  Come on, girl! -  Let's go!
加油  加油  格蕾西
- Come on. - Come on, Gracie!
加油
Come on!
冲啊
Let's go!
嘿
Hey.
对  我看见了
Yeah, I saw it.
既然看见了  为什么还这么做
If you saw it, why you doing it?
伙计  我现在没心情
Buddy, I'm in no mood.
没心情  是吗  没错
- Oh, you're in no mood, huh? - That's right.
没心情是我的口头禅
"I'm in no mood" is my fucking motto.
是吗
Is that right?
满意了吧  这下是乱扔垃圾了
- You happy? - Well, now that's littering.
该死
For fuck's sake, dude.
去找点别的事做吧
Go find something else to do.
对  要有耐心
That's it, just be patient.
步伐不错
Good stride.
步伐好吗  步伐很好
- Yeah. - She got a good stride?
是的
Yes, she does.
马丁内斯仍然领先
And it's Martinez that remains
冲在最前面
out in front.
走内道
Take the inside!
加油  格蕾西
Come on, Gracie.
米勒发起冲刺
And Miller makes a move.
就是这样
That's it!
德克萨斯基督教大学的米勒冲出重围
Miller from TCU breaks out in front of the pack.
堪萨斯大学的戴维斯紧随其后
Davis from Kansas, trying to keep pace.
冲过终点线的是
And at the finish line it's gonna be
德克萨斯基督教大学的格蕾西·米勒
Gracie Miller of TCU!
耶
Whoo!
过来
Come on.
你还在吗  在呢
- You still there? -  Yeah, yeah.
这么做是对的  蒙蒂
It's the right thing to do, Monty.
也能传达正确的信息  我会这么做
And it sends the right message. I'd do it.
现在把电话放下
Put the phone down now.
好啊  我放在办公桌上
Yeah, sure, I'll just set it here on my credenza.
你觉得如何  蒙蒂
What do you think, Monty?
好
Yeah.
就这么做
Do it.
让内特拟文件
Have Nate paper it.
转过去  好好我转
-  Turn around. - Yeah. Yeah, I will.
好吧 回头聊 拜
All right, I'll talk to you later. Bye.
你来让我转啊
Make me.
乐意之至  真的吗
- Be my fucking pleasure. - Really?
要不你去换换尿布吧
Why don't you go empty some fucking bedpans?
我的车来了
My ride's here.
皮特 这家伙找你麻烦吗
This guy giving you trouble, Pete?
这家伙嘴巴很欠
This guy's got a mouth on him.
你老婆最爱我这一点
That's your wife's favorite thing about me.
除了我那活儿  祝你愉快
Other than my dick. Have a good day.
走吧 老兄
Let's go, bud.
跟当地警察
Telling the local PD
说滚蛋
to go fuck themselves
有点目光短浅 你不觉得吗
is pretty shortsighted, don't you think?
我憋着一肚子气想发泄
Well, I needed to give it to somebody,
他刚好撞上来
and he was the closest one, so...
我建议你找机会请那小子喝杯酒
I recommend you buy that boy a beer your first chance.
他可是很记仇的
That one got a mean memory.
是吗  好吧 记住了
That right? All right, noted.
嘿
Hey.
我女儿在干什么
What's my daughter doing?
在破坏我的注意力
Napalming my concentration.
她发现了游泳池
She has discovered the pool.
管住你自己别偷看
Well, see if you can manage enough self-control
好吗
to not gawk, all right?
我正背对着窗户呢
I am facing away from the window.
好样的
Good man.
蒙蒂已经批准我们向死者家属
So, Monty cleared us to make
支付抚恤金
bereavement payments to the families.
已经确认死者身份了吗
They identify the bodies?
通过排除法确认的
By process of elimination.
多少钱  每家25万
- How much? - 250 for each family.
把死者家属的姓名发给我
Well, give me names of next of kin,
我转交给会计部
I'll forward them to accounting.
内特 你知道他们是谁
Well, you know the names, Nate.
梅迪纳团队维修那口井
Medina crew serviced that well.
该死  死了谁
Shit. Which one died?
全都死了
They all died.
回头再聊 好吗
I'll talk to you later, all right?
你们这有椰子油吗
Do y'all have any coconut oil?
椰子油  用来烹饪的吗
- Coconut oil? - Like for cooking?
我不是用来烹饪  但你想的话也可以
I ain't gonna use it to cook, but you could if you wanted to.
我们不怎么做饭
Well, none of us do much, uh, much cooking.
介意我找找吗
Well, do you mind if I check?
随意吧  当然可以
Feel free. You bet.
这不是我要找的
This is not what I was looking for,
但临时用一用也行
but it'll work in a pinch.
我必须弄清楚
I have to know.
我去客厅工作
I'm gonna work in the living room.
你觉得他们知道要听到这个消息吗
You think they have any idea this news is coming?
虽然不知道具体是什么
They don't know this is coming,
但肯定知道有事发生了
but they know something's coming.
是哪一个
Which one?
玛丽亚在吗
Is Maria here?
阿丽安娜在吗
How about Ariana?
在屋里陪孩子
With the babies, inside.
我们能进去吗
Can we come inside?
还喝啤酒还是想来点烈酒
Sticking with beer or you want something stronger?
我已经戒酒了  啤酒就行
I quit drinking. I'll stick with beer.
你知道啤酒里也有酒精吧
You know, there's alcohol in that, right?
这是超清淡啤酒
It's a Michelob Ultra.
橙汁的酒精度都比这高
There's more alcohol in orange juice.
我不是在评判你 伙计
I ain't judging, buddy.
我已经戒酒八年了
I mean, I've been on the wagon eight years.
我只是说喝啤酒也算喝酒
I'm just saying, drinking beer is still drinking.
我告诉你
Well, I tell you what, bud,
你看我喝六瓶这玩意
you watch me drink six of these sons of bitches,
明晚我再来这里
and I'll come back in here tomorrow night
喝六杯威士忌 你再看看
and drink six whiskeys, and you tell me
有什么差别
if you notice a fucking difference.
我相信你说的
I'll take your word for it.
超清淡啤酒
Michelob Ultra.
嘿  嘿
- Hey. -  Hey.
你没给我回电话  抱歉
- You didn't call me back. - Sorry.
他醒了而且意识清醒 会观察一晚
He's awake and alert. They're keeping him overnight.
你那点小伤怎么样了
And how's your little boo-boo?
比早上短了一英吋
An inch shorter than it was this morning.
这一句话就概括了我们的婚姻
If that doesn't sum up our marriage in a sentence.
我敢说我还比你嫁的
Well, I bet you I still got a few inches
那个胖子提款机长几英吋呢
on that fat-ass ATM you married.
你知道那句老话
Well, you know the old saying,
银行账户上每多一个逗号
"Every comma in your bank account
就能让你那里多长两英吋
adds two inches to your penis,"
那你可要赶紧追上来了
which is to say you're way behind.
这话说得好
That's good to know.
我觉得我应该在那里
I feel like I should be there.
我该过去吗  我觉得很内疚
Should I be there? I feel guilty.
你该内疚
You should feel guilty.
我值得放个假  休什么假
- I deserve a vacation. - From what?
你在那边做的事
You're doing exactly the same fucking thing
跟在家做的一样 只是不能喝自来水
you do at home, except you can't drink the water.
所以你是说我该过去
So you're saying I should come?
有必要吗  没有
Do you need to? No.
不过你是他们的母亲 如果你觉得
But you're their mother, so if you feel like
自己该在这里  那就该过来
you ought to be here, you probably should come.
你想让我过去吗
Do you want me to come?
安吉拉 你来不来我都无所谓
Angela, I couldn't care less if you come or not.
我收回前言
I stand corrected.
这句话才是我们婚姻的真实写照
That is the sentence that sums up our marriage.
明天见 混蛋
I'll see you tomorrow, you fucking asshole.
等不及了
I can't wait.
是
Yeah.
汤姆·诺里斯吗
Tom Norris?
汤米
Tommy.
丽贝卡·法尔科内 谢泼德·黑斯廷斯
Rebecca Falcone, Shepherd-Hastings.
是的
Oh, yeah.
嘿
Hey, uh,
我们给你安排了房间 但是
listen, we got you a room at the house, but--
我已经订了酒店
I got a hotel.
周末能见面吗
Can you meet up over the weekend?
现在就能见面  如果你想的话
I can meet you right now if you want to.
在哪
Where?
派奇咖啡厅
Patch Cafe.
离希尔顿多远
How far from the Hilton?
米德兰任何地方都是15分钟车程
Everything in Midland's 15 minutes from everything else.
那里见
I'll meet you there.
好的
All right.
你好 我找汤米·诺里斯
Hi, I'm here to see a Tommy Norris.
吧台戴牛仔帽的那位
Cowboy hat at the bar.
我这么好认吗
I'm that easy to spot, huh?
一眼就能看到
Wasn't difficult.
喝点什么  好啊
- You want a drink? - Yeah.
苏打水
A club soda.
伙计 给这位女士来杯苏打水
Hey, bud? Club soda for the lady.
我提醒你一下
Just so you know,
这是无酒精饮料
that is a nonalcoholic drink.
这一定是你的兴趣爱好
This must be your hobby
因为你肯定不是冲着小费来的
'cause you damn sure don't want a fucking tip.
希望你别称呼我为"女士"
I'd prefer if you didn't refer to me as "the lady."
我说错了吗
Oh, did I guess wrong?
非常抱歉 先生
I'm so sorry, sir,
顺便恭喜你的整形医生
and hats off to the plastic surgeon
成功切除了你的喉结
that shaved that Adam's apple.
我在油田的第一天
My first day in the oil fields,
就没让我失望
and it doesn't disappoint.
跟我想的一样粗俗
It is as offensive as I imagined.
你知道你为谁工作吗
You know the sharks you work with?
你们这些没有灵魂的混蛋
You soulless fucks represent
为本拉登家族服务 看在上帝的份上
the Bin Laden family, for Christ's sakes.
我叫你"女士"你该谢谢我
You should be thanking me for calling you "lady."
在你这行可能再也听不到这样的话了
You may never hear it again in your line of work.
抱歉 但我今天失去了三个朋友
I'm sorry, but I lost three friends
还断了一根手指
and a finger today, so...
所以我有点暴躁
I'm a little edgy.
我不知道他们是你朋友
I didn't know they were friends.
他们就是我朋友
They were friends.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们需要把重点从TTP转移到
We need to shift our focus from TTP
今早的事故上
to the incident this morning.
这更容易引起关注
It lends itself to more exposure.
你是律师
You're the attorney.
明天能带我去事故现场吗
Can you take me to the incident site tomorrow?
现在就能带你去
I can take you right now.
太好了
Great.
好  我们走吧
- All right. - Let's go.
伙计  嗯
-  Hey, bud? -  Mm-hmm.
让我来付账  好
- Let me take care of this. - Yep.
要找零吗
You want change?
你居然能面不改色地说这话
I can't believe you said that with a straight face.
我他妈当然要变革
Of course I want fucking change.
抱歉车里有灰
Sorry about the dust.
这是租的
It's a rental.
除了保险公司和郡警长
So, who besides insurance companies
还有谁会调查这起事故
and county sheriff investigate this?
所有人  职业安全局  铁路委员会  公共安全部
Hell, everybody. OSHA, Railroad Commission, DPS.
你负责石油责任纠纷案
Shouldn't you know all this shit
不该了解这些吗
if you're litigating a petroleum liability case?
我专攻责任链案件
My specialty is chain of liability,
这适用于TTP案
which applies to the TTP case.
但在这里不太适用
Not so much here.
这事发生时我在飞机上
This happened when I was on the plane.
也许他们该派另一个律师来
Maybe they should send another attorney.
我听说有人活了下来
I understand one of them survived.
是的
Yeah.
我能跟他谈谈吗
Can I speak with him?
今天不行  什么时候可以
- Not today. - When?
等他他妈的出院再说
How about when he gets out of the fucking hospital?
还有什么事吗
Anything else?
从这里你能看出什么
What can you tell from this?
从油井看不出什么
From the well? Nothing.
从火势类型来看呢
From the type of fire?
有泄漏
There was a leak.
一个钻井工用锤子和扳手
A roughneck created a spark
试图打开阀门时引起了火花
when he tried to open the valve with a hammer and a wrench.
他为什么要用锤子开
Why would he try to open it with a hammer?
因为这他妈就是开阀门的方法
'Cause that's how you open the fucking thing.
这看起来不太安全
Doesn't seem very safe.
是不安全  所以他们年薪18万
It's not very safe. That's why they make 180 grand a year.
为了这点钱冒生命危险不值得
That's not enough money to risk your life on.
对你来说可能是
Yeah, for you, maybe.
但对只上过初中的重刑犯来说
For a felon with an eighth-grade education,
这就是中彩票
it's a fucking lottery ticket.
对于那些油企经理来说
And for an oil company whose manager
明知故犯  派员工去违反职业安全标准的故障油井
knowingly sends employees to faulty wells
这就是一场价值数亿的诉讼
that violate OSHA standards,
那整个该死的行业都有罪
it's a nine-figure lawsuit.
所以整个行业都该死
Well, then the whole goddamn industry's guilty.
我是站在你这边的  汤米
I'm on your side, Tommy.
你需要明白这一点
You need to understand that.
我很清楚
Yeah, I understand plenty.
你和站在我这边差得远着呢
You're the farthest thing from being on my side.
该死  该死
Son of a bitch. Son of a bitch.
信息  教育
Information, education,
和想像力是对抗石油和天然气行业冲击的
and imagination are the weapons against the assault
武器
on oil and natural gas.
但他们用来对付我们的武器
But the weapon being used against us
更加危险
is far more dangerous.
那就是情绪
Emotion.
情绪是环保运动的矛头
Emotion is the spear of the green movement.
你一开始是怎么把我拉来的
How did you rope me into this in the first place?
这不是个约会吗
Wasn't this a...? This was a date?
来嘛宝贝  这就是个约会  嗯
- Come on, babe. It is a date. - Mm-hmm.
这只是约会的开始
It's just the beginning of a date.
哦  约会结束时
- Oh. - The end of the date
才是最精彩的部分  你知道的
is when the date gets fun, you know that.
最好是这样
It better.
主流媒体已经抛弃了
Mainstream media has abandoned
支持事实的证据
evidence supporting facts
他们惊慌失措 因为观众都转向了
in their panic to prevent the exodus
推特和抖音
of their audience to Twitter and TikTok
作为可靠的新闻来源
as reliable news sources.
这还是在俄罗斯之前
And that's before Russia...
该死  中国
- Shit. - ...China,
伊朗 真主党  需要接电话吗
- Iran, Hezbollah... - Do you need to get that?
哈马斯 基地组织  不 我不确定
- ...Hamas, Al-Qaeda... - No, I'm not sure.
他们在社交媒体上充斥着
...all of them flooding social media...
我觉得我马上就知道了
I feel like I'm about to find out.
伪装成气候变化恐慌的
...with propaganda masquerading
宣传
- as fear of climate change. -
是的  我想我得接这个
Yep. I do think I have to get this.
好吧
Okay.
帮我占个座
Will you save my seat?
看你去多久了
Depends on how long you're gone.
可以说是最没文化的群众
...in arguably the most uneducated populace...
嘿  让我一会儿回你电话
Hey. Let me call you right back.
我得找个安静的地方
Yeah, I got to find someplace quiet.
什么事  什么事
-  Yeah? - What is it?
你他妈觉得是什么事
The fuck do you think it is?
你派来这条员工关系部门的毒蛇
Who is this employee relations pit viper
是来咬我的吗
you sent out here to bite me?
我按你说的打给了钱德勒
Uh, I called Chandler like you said.
但他们没派他来
Well, they didn't fucking send him!
他们派人来整我
They sent somebody out here to hang me out.
你没有一口油井能通过职业安全标准  蒙蒂
You don't have a well that will pass OSHA standards, Monty.
一口都没有
Not fucking one.
我是个混蛋  蒙蒂
I'm a lot of shit, Monty,
但我不是他妈的替罪羊  明白吗
but I ain't a fucking patsy, you understand me?
我打给了克莱
I called Clay,
他说他正飞去找你
who said he was flying to you.
我不知道他们为什么没派克莱
Now, I don't know who they sent that isn't Clay,
但我会查清楚
but I will find out.
很好
Good.
听着
Now, look,
我们这行业总是危机不断
our business is one of constant crisis
偶尔会有短暂的成功
interrupted by brief periods of intense success.
这你应该比任何人都清楚
You should know that better than anyone else.
今天是很糟糕
Now, today was a rough one.
我能理解你情绪激动
And I can understand why you might be emotional,
但别让情绪
but don't let your emotions
让你忘了谁是老板
confuse you as to who the boss is.
老板是我
The boss is me,
别他妈再对我大吼大叫
and don't you ever raise your fucking voice at me again.
亲爱的 我在回家路上
I'm on the way home, honey.
我快饿死了
Yeah, I'm starving.
不是那种"我好饿好像要饿死了"的感觉
Like not, "I'm so hungry, I feel like I'm starving."
是真的快饿死了
I'm starving.
我脸色都发白了
Like, my skin looks pale,
器官都要衰竭了  厨房里
- my organs are shutting down. - Well, there's
有很多吃的 亲爱的
a kitchen full of food in there, honey.
爸爸 厨房里全是致癌的加工食品
Daddy, there's a kitchen full of processed cancer bombs.
谁会整箱整箱买多力多滋啊
And who orders Doritos by the palette?
我需要蛋白质
I need protein.
橱柜里有蛋白质
There's protein in the cupboard.
维也纳香肠不算蛋白质 爸爸
Vienna sausages is not protein, Daddy.
这是那些连做热狗都嫌恶心的
You know, it's all the parts of a cow
牛肉残渣做的
that are too gross to be in hot dogs.
是猪肉 不过我不想争这个
Well, it's pork, but I'm not gonna have that fight.
要我给你带点别的吗
You want me to pick you something up?
能给我带一个动物风味生菜包汉堡吗
Could you get me an animal-style Whataburger wrapped in lettuce?
动物什么
An animal what?
就是特制酱料
It's, like, special sauce.
不要面包 用生菜包着
And there's no bun. They, like, wrap it in lettuce.
生菜都是切碎的 怎么包
How can they wrap it in lettuce? Their lettuce is shredded.
我每次要他们都会做的
Well, they always do it when I ask.
他们会去后厨拿整片生菜
They just go in the back, and they get the whole lettuce.
咱俩活在不同的世界里
You and I live in different worlds.
他们肯定要我滚蛋
They'll tell me to fuck myself.
要不我给你买个汉堡
Why don't I just get you a burger,
你自己扔掉面包
and you throw the buns away?
好吧 那就这样
Yeah. Yeah, I guess we could do that.
再给我三根薯条和一杯健怡可乐
And could you get me three fries and a Diet Coke?
所以
So,
你不吃面包 却要三份
you won't eat the buns, but you'll eat three orders
薯条  不是
- of fries? - No!
我要三根薯条 你得挑出三根
I want three fries. You have to pick out three,
其他的都扔掉
and then throw the rest of them away.
好吧 还要什么吗
Okay. Anything else?
谢谢爸爸
Thank you, Daddy.
你快到了吗
Are you close?
没 这还得多花十分钟
No, and this is gonna add ten minutes to the trip, too.
那就15分钟
So, like, 15?
一个小时
Like, an hour.
An hour?!
希望我还活着
I hope I'm still alive.
这些挑战
Well,
会让你变得更坚强
these are the challenges that harden you
以应对生命中的不幸 亲爱的
for life's tragedies, honey.
待会见
I'll see you soon.
好 谢谢 我爱你
Okay, thank you. I love you.
我也爱你 亲爱的
Okay, love you, too, honey.
我很快就到  你能快点吗
- I'll be there soon. - Will you hurry?
好 我会快点的
Yeah, I'll hurry.
好 爱你 拜
Okay. Love you. Bye.
爱你 拜
- Love you. Bye. -
天啊
Goddamn!
妈的
Shit.
你要去哪
Where you headed?
脱衣舞俱乐部
To the strip club.
咱们女儿在那里
While our daughter's there?
对 她要来见我
Yeah, she's meeting me there.
我觉得是时候让她见识下生活的阴暗面了
I thought it's time she sees the darker side of life.
你到底要去哪
Where are you really headed?
我要回家
I'm going home.
你看起来很累
You look tired.
这是有原因的
There's a reason for that.
我其实不一定要去
I don't really need to come.
我有必要去吗
Do I need to come?
我说了你不需要来
I already told you you don't need to come.
如果我想来呢
What if I want to come?
你为什么想来
Why would you want to do that?
如果我就是想呢
What if I did?
你要从卡波圣卢卡斯来到德克萨斯的米德兰
You want to leave Cabo and come to Midland, Texas
在有三个室友的出租屋里和你前夫上床
to fuck your ex-husband in a rent house with three roommates?
我怎么觉得不太可能
Why do I doubt that?
你就不能盼着我来吗
Can't you just fucking want me to come?
你就不能这样吗
Why can't you do that?
亲爱的 我当然想让你来
Oh, honey, I want you to come, believe me.
我只是知道你不会来
I mean, I just know you'll never do it.
这让我很心痛 我真的很想让你来
Breaks my heart. I really want you to.
我打赌你待会会想这事的
You'll think about it later, I bet.
我得和女儿睡一张床
Well, since I'm sharing a bed with our daughter,
所以我最好别想这事了
I hope I don't think about it later.
好吧 晚安 安吉
Okay. Good night, Angie.
嗯 晚安
Mm-hmm. Good night.
感谢上帝
Thank you, God.
拿着
There you go.
我说服他们用生菜包的
I talked them into the lettuce thing in back there.
你怎么做到的  给他们看了你的照片
- How'd you do that? - Showed 'em your picture.
爸爸 我说要三根薯条 这里有一整份
Daddy, I said three fries. There's a whole order in here.
其他的是我的  那样的话
- Well, the rest are for me. - Well,
我肯定会说服你给我的 爸爸
I'm just gonna talk you out of them, Daddy.
你得把它们扔掉
You need to throw 'em away.
现在 现在就扔
Now. Now!
你八岁的时候这样很可爱
You know, this shit was cute when you were eight,
但现在我满脑子想的都是你第一次结婚
but now all I think about's your first marriage
那个可怜的家伙受够这些事后
and the skid marks that poor bastard leaves
留下的刹车印
after he's had a few years of this shit.
你讨厌是因为你是我父亲
It annoys you because you're my father,
你不想和我上床
and you don't want to have sex with me.
但其他男孩会把这些要求看作是
But other boys look at these chores like...
小小的寻宝游戏
little treasure hunts.
对了 你哥住院了 我忘了告诉你
Oh, your brother's in the hospital. I forgot to tell you.
对不起  在哪
- Sorry about that. - Where?
这里
Here.
他在米德兰干什么  为我工作
- What's he doing in Midland? - Working for me.
他不是五月才毕业吗
But he doesn't graduate till May.
他永远都毕不了业了 他退学了
He don't graduate ever. He dropped out.
他想在油田工作
He wants to work in the patch.
他真是个废物
He is such a loser.
爸爸 我不是那个意思
Daddy, I didn't... I didn't mean it like that.
让我告诉你一件事 亲爱的
Let me tell you something, honey.
在油田工作的人分两种
There's two types of people that work in the patch--
梦想家和失败者
dreamers and losers.
以前整个国家都是这样
Used to be that way in the whole nation.
失败者都西行 不是死就是成功
Failures headed out West to either die or succeed.
一直到加利福尼亚
All the way to California.
但那里现在已经没有梦想家了
But there's not any dreamers out there anymore,
只有小偷和傻瓜
just thieves and fools.
梦想家们现在来这里
This is where dreamers come now.
失败者来这里寻求成功
And losers come here to win.
你想当哪一种
Which one are you gonna be?
梦想家
A dreamer.
第一次尝试总是会失败
First attempt's always a failure,
所以你会先成为失败者
so it means you're gonna be a loser.
不知道你会怎么做
Wonder what you'll do then.
今晚你睡我的房间 我睡沙发
You take my room tonight, and I'll, uh, take the couch.
现在你应该明白了
Well, I guess now
我说的"钻井工人很危险"是什么意思
you understand what I mean by "roughnecking's dangerous."
这话从一个每天抽两包烟的人嘴里说出来
Says the two-pack-a-day smoker.
再过三个月你就能拿到
In three months, you could've had
地质学学位了 你却
a fucking degree in geology, and you...
我不需要学位
I don't need a degree.
我学到了需要的地质知识
I learned all I need about geology.
我不想教这些 我想亲身实践
I don't want to teach the shit, I want to live it.
我想做土地中介
I want to be a landman.
像蒙蒂·米勒那样的人
Well, for every Monty Miller,
一百个里面只有一个 好吗
there's a hundred of me, all right?
你和蒙蒂的区别就是他没有放弃
The only difference between you and Monty is Monty didn't quit.
我和蒙蒂的区别在于
The difference in me
我没有该死的信托基金
and Monty is I don't have a fucking trust fund.
我不是主动退出的  而是被迫流血退场的
I didn't quit, I bled out.
而且我也没见你去投机
And besides, I don't see you speculating
或者四处寻找机会  或争取矿产权
or banging on doors, or hustling mineral rights.
不  你只是钻井队的新手
No, you're the worm on a drill crew.
不好意思  你曾经是
Excuse me, you were.
而你的队伍第一天就全军覆没了
And your crew is fucking dead on day one.
这就是给你的警示
So, take the fucking hint!
如果我想将来经营一家石油公司
If I'm going to run an oil company one day,
就必须了解每个环节是如何运作的
I need to know how every aspect of it works.
勘探
The surveys,
建造钻井平台
making the drill pad,
转移设备  安置工人
moving the gear, housing the crew,
安装钻机  封井
setting the drill, capping the well,
维护油井  所有这些
maintaining the well, all of it.
所以  经营石油公司  这就是你现在的计划
So, run an oil company. That's your plan now.
这是我的梦想
That's the dream.
我还没有具体计划
I don't have a plan yet.
好吧  你比大多数人都走得更远
Well, you're closer than most.
我需要帮个忙
I need a favor.
你能帮我个忙吗
Will you do me a favor?
要看是什么忙
Depends on what the favor is.
让我去另一个钻井队
Put me on another crew.
你知道  很多人会因为
You know, a lot of people are gonna blame you
发生的事情责怪你
for what happened.
每当出事  他们总是责怪新手
Anytime something goes wrong, they always blame the worm.
就让他们说吧
Let me.
好吧  我会给你找个队伍
All right, I'll find you a crew.
听着  你妹妹来镇上了
Listen, your sister's in town.
要不要回家看看她
You want to run by the house and see her?
我宁愿你送我去医院
I'd rather you drive me to the hospital
让他们再给我插导尿管
so they can run that catheter back up my dick.
好吧  这也行
Fair enough.
要去咖啡馆喝杯啤酒吗
You want to go by the cafe and get a beer?
现在才早上八点
It's eight in the morning.
今天是周日
It's Sunday.
你还有什么事要做吗
What else you got to do?
为什么不呢
Why not?
好啊
All right.
ed3000.cc 原创翻译出品  参与：贾婷、会飞的猪仔  校对：巴萨姆